sportingbet.com 2008-05-09

# Sportingbet.com - online sports betting, poker, casino and instant win games.

**PRIVACY STATEMENT**   
SPORTINGBET.COM has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy for our uses. The following privacy statement discloses our information gathering and dissemention practices for this website: [www.sportingbet.com](http://www.sportingbet.com/)

The following Privacy Statement explains: 

  1. What personally identifiable information SPORTINGBET.COM collects. 
  2. What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site. 
  3. What organization collects the information. 
  4. How SPORTINGBET.COM uses the information. 
  5. With whom SPORTINGBET.COM may share user information. 
  6. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  7. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under SPORTINGBET.COM control. 
  8. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact :   

**Information Collection and Use Information Collection**   
Sportingbet Group is the sole owner of the information collected on [www.sportingbet.com](http://www.sportingbet.com/)

Registration   
In order to use this Web site, a user must first become a member via 'Account Set Up'. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as a name and an email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which the user has expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as gender), and unique identifiers (such as, username and password), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site. When a user wishes to deposit money into their account electronically, we need to know the user's credit card number and expiration date in order to process the user's transaction and allow the user to begin wagering. If we have trouble processing a wager, the information is used to contact the user. 

**Information Use**   
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. When placing a wager, or logging into our secure server, your IP address is tracked against your user ID for the dual purposes of preventing fraud and creating an audit trail. This information is not used or accessed for any other purposes. 

We may also use information such as email addresses to alert our customers of special promotions that we may be running or to inform you of any news or changes that might affect your gaming experiences. If you would like to be excluded from our email list, please email [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com)

**Profile**   
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with other third parties. 

**Cookies**   
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.   
<http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm>

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 

**Log Files**   
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service. 

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**   
Our third party advertising company employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users' personally identifiable information. 

Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the advertising company would match the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be given to the advertising company. 

In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please email: [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com)

**Communications from the Site**   
Special Offers and Updates

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify username. Established members will occasionally receive information on services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please email [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com) to direct you to the respective 'opt' out of such communications. 

Newsletter   
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please email [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com) to opt out. 

Service Announcements   
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. Users may opt-out of these communications. Please email [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com) to opt out. 

Customer Service   
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.   
We will not use any information obtained about users to encourage irresponsible gaming behaviour. 

**Sharing**   
Legal Disclaimer   
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law or our regulator wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, an order from our regulator or legal process served on our Web site. 

Third Party Intermediaries   
We use a credit card processing company to process bets. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

Business Transitions   
In the event SPORTINGBET.COM goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. 

**Choice/Opt-out**   
Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, our account Set Up form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so users who place a wager with us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com)

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party. 

**Links**   
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we Sportingbet PLC are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

**Surveys & Contests**   
From time-to-time, our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used shared with the contest sponsors to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use users' personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Tell-A-Friend**   
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's email address. SPORTINGBET.COM will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. 

**Security**   
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just 'surfing'. 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every year, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users' information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment. 

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com)

**Children's Guidelines**

  1. SportingBet believes in providing a protected environment, it is recognized that gambling is an exciting adult leisure pursuit. It is illegal for anyone under the age of 18 to gamble with SportingBet. We reserve the right to ask for verification documents from any customer and may suspend an account until such proof is received. 
  2. Please note that anyone under the age of 18 found to be gambling with SportingBet will have any winnings forfeited. 

**Data Protection**   
Under the Data Protection Act 1998 (UK legislation), (Bailiwick of Guernsey) Law 2001 and EU privacy and the OECD Guidelines on the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Data Flow of Personal Data we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorized access to it. 

**Supplementation of Information**   
In order for this Web site to properly fulfill its obligation to users it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from third party sources. Therefore, we use TRUSTMARK to verify a user's identity and address to eliminate fraudulent transactions. 

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**   
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the [member information page] or by emailing our Customer Support at [admin@sportingbet.com](mailto:admin@sportingbet.com). 

**Notification of Changes**   
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

**Customer Charter**   
Sportingbet promises to ensure complete openness and clarity in all its financial relationships with customers. Sportingbet will offer odds on all mainstream sporting events and these will be competitive with other major bookmakers. Sportingbet maintains 24 hour call centers, available in a wide range of languages to resolve all customer matters as quickly as possible. In the event that there is no amicable agreement in a dispute, Sportingbet agrees to abide by independent arbitration. Sportingbet respects the privacy of all its customers and commits itself to protect any data about customers from outside parties. 

**Contact Information**   
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 

**Phone** +44 020 7184 1800   
**Fax** +44 020 7184 1810   
**Email** admin@sportingbet.com 

**Postal Address**   
Sportingbet Plc   
4th Floor   
45 Moorfields   
London   
EC2Y 9AE 

Close window

Sportingbet no longer accepts any bets from the US. Click here for more information.

© 2007 Internet Opportunity Entertainment (Sports) Limited and Interactive Sports (C.I.) Limited. All rights reserved   
[Sportingbet](http://www.sportingbet.com/ "Sportingbet") Group - The World's Leading Online Gambling Company   

Warning: Gambling involves risk. By gambling on this website, you run the risk that you may lose money or suffer psychological injuries. You gamble at your own risk. 

Minimum Browser requirements: [FireFox](http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/) v2 or IE Explorer v6.0, [Flash player 8](http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash) and JavaScript enabled   
Sportsbook members must be 18 or over
